Damilola Adeniye

Software Engineer / IT Support Engineer

Contact

Address

Lagos, Lagos, 100001

Phone

080-745-08921

E-mail

dammyadeniye@gmail.com

www

https://robodam.github.io/portfolio/

Skills

Application support

Remote Technical Support

Remote support

Search Engine Optimization

Troubleshooting

Technical Support

Responsive design

SQL platforms

Web Security

Virtualization

I strongly believe in hard work. I am team player and I crave to provide the best services, bringing the best result and qualitative responses, passionate about achieving a challenging professional responsibility that allows meaningful contributions to the development of organization by providing support of all IT Needs that offers growth opportunities and allows me to utilize my leadership skills and experience. To seek and maintain a full-time position that offers professional challenges utilizing interpersonal skills, excellent time management and problem-solving skills.

Work History

2020-10 -2021-06

(TEK EXPERT)Technical Support Engineer

Pwara Nwang, Lagos Island, Lagos

- Using tools like Service Desk, LCS, App Insights, Kusto, and Azure DevOps to help a variety of business partners.
- Identify and submit bugs in the product to product group, along with design changes to improve the overall experience.
- Collaborate with multiple SME engineers across the product to assist customers to a faster resolution.
- Developed training and content guides to help our vendor team achieve guicker case resolutions.
- Confidently communicated solutions, workarounds, and configurations to our partners and customers Responsible for the customer support experience with Microsoft Own, troubleshoot and solve customer technical issues, using collaboration, troubleshooting best practices and transparency within and across teams (e.g.
- Swarming).
- Identify cases that require escalation (either technically or strategically).
- Create and maintain incident management requests to product group/engineering group.
- Contribute to case deflection initiatives, automation and other digital self-help assets to improve.

2017-02 -2020-10 (Tranter IT)Lafarge Holcime Helpdesk Analyst React js

PHP development

<u>Nodejs</u>

Microsoft Packages

Banji Ajiye, Lagos, Lagos

- Joined a team of professionals in a rigorous training on help desk support, service desk and all that entails IT service and its infrastructure.
- Provided Application support and contributed technical support while on site and ability to manage 150,000 client.
- Active directory.
- ITIL.
- Customer Service.
- Helpdesk support.
- E-Banking(POS support).
- 1st line Support-troubleshooting of IT Related problems from in-house software to hardware, such as laptops, desktops and printers.
- Involved in the rollout of software updates and patches.
- Setting-up and deployment of Laptops, printers, projectors and other PC and hardware Peripherals to new and existing users using the company checklist.
- Deploying new hardware, server backups & evaluating new software & security risks.
- Raising Tickets on SERVICENOW (SNOW) and assigning to higher level when issue is beyond Level-1 Job scope.
- Management of Staff C.U.G Lines.
- Tracking of Equipment inventory Lists.
- Performing End user Network troubleshooting and Support.
- Performing daily Backup of all servers National Youth Service.
- Atakumosa Senior High School Osu, Osun State.

2017-10 - (Peacock Travels)Customer/Marketing 2017-12 Executive

Festus duroseye, Lagos, Lagos

- Provided the SEO to optimize their platform.
- Ability to generate traffic.
- Monitored the activities on the site using goggle analytic.
- Boosted brand awareness and generated leads

- while managing internal and external marketing campaigns and programs.
- Communicated marketing strategy and campaign performance to verify alignment with corporate sales objectives.
- Maintained a complete database of all files, contacts and project materials.
- Planned and executed marketing campaigns to target groups, areas and the wider community.

2015-11 - (Atakumosa High Sch) Computer Science 2016-11 Tutor

Eddy, Atakumosa, Osun

- Conduct assigned classes at the times scheduled.
- Worked cooperativeness with school administrators, students, parents, other Teachers and colleagues.
- Implement designated support to the school computer laboratory and its.
- Motivated students towards learning and studying to build self-confidence and reduce fear of failure
- Identified learning needs and implemented fun and engaging learning activities to help students advance
- Stressed importance of good study habits by encouraging students to create personalized study plans
- Provided appropriate learning materials for students
- Collaborated with parents to create tutoring sessions appropriate for student's age, learning preference and learning style
- Updated required logs and student documentation to keep records accurate and current
- Provided early intervention assistance to struggling students
- Provided homework assistance using specific curriculum and materials
- Helped students prepare for routine and standardized tests, including college entrance exams

2013-10 - (Robodam)Freelancer Full Stack Web Current Developer

Damilola Adeniye, Lagos, Lagos

- Web Developer, I'm a Full-Stack web, mobile and desktop developer with a Diploma of Specialist in Information Technologies, based in Nigeria, Lagos.
- I started working in web technologies in 2014, I used to work with plenty of different stacks, technologies and libraries.
- My previous employment and management experience provides me with leadership skills that allow me to effectively communicate with others to achieve our goals. In addition, it has provided me with the knowledge of understanding and communicating with customers to satisfy their needs.
- I am a fast learner who enjoys challenges and thrives in a fast-paced, goal-oriented environment.
 Currently have experience working with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, Web pack, MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, AngularJS, Angular 2, Typescript, ReactJS, Docker and WordPress and lots more about both backend and frontend parts of web application development.
- I'm comfortable discussing technical solutions, taking, and be responsible for the taken decision.
- Looking for challenging projects and delivering complete working solutions for clients

Education

2012-10 -2015-11

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Ajayi Crowther University - Lagos

Certifications

2015-11	[Computer Professional Registration], [Council of Nigeria.] - [Graduate Member]]
2021-06	[The Complete Web Developer in 2020: Zero to Mastery], [Udemy] - [June 2020]
2021-01	[Learn Ethical Hacking From Scratch] Z-Security
2017-06	[ITIL(Information Technology Infrastructure

Library)]Hawlett Packard Enterprise(HPE)

2013-10

[Oracle Database 11g (OCA)] United Global resource limited (UGRL). 91 Allen avenue Lagos.

Accomplishments

- https://thecravingideas.com/
- https://robodam.github.io/portfolio/
- https://robodam.github.io/Joksnail/